<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0">

<channel>
  <title>We are Knytt - Blog</title>
  <link>https://weareknytt.com/blog/</link>
  <description>Blog about graphic design for board games</description>
  <item>
    <title>A picture is worth a thousand words</title>
    <link>https://weareknytt.com/blog/a-picture-is-worth-a-thousand-words</link>
    <description>The saying “A picture is worth a thousand words” refers to a picture often being more effective at conveying a complex idea than words are. This is as true within board games as in other fields, and applicable both in rulebooks and on components.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Iconifying everything - A review of the graphic design in Terraforming Mars</title>
    <link>https://weareknytt.com/blog/graphic-design-and-illustration</link>
    <description>A lot of people in the board gaming industry seem to be confused about the difference between graphic design and illustrations. Because of this, I want to clarify the terms, and explain why both are necessary for a great game. In short, illustrations are there to make the game pretty and the graphic design is there to make the game understandable.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>Graphic design and illustrations - What’s the difference?</title>
    <link>https://weareknytt.com/blog/graphic-design-and-illustration</link>
    <description>A lot of people in the board gaming industry seem to be confused about the difference between graphic design and illustrations. Because of this, I want to clarify the terms, and explain why both are necessary for a great game. In short, illustrations are there to make the game pretty and the graphic design is there to make the game understandable.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>A card for every occasion - Situation based card design</title>
    <link>https://weareknytt.com/blog/a-card-for-every-occasion</link>
    <description>We need to talk about card design. You might think that designing a card is just slapping all the necessary information on the card in some arbitrary way, but that’s almost as far from the truth as you can come. You have to customize the card design to how the game is being played, and how the cards are being used.</description>
  </item>
  <item>
    <title>UX design in board games - Why does it matter?</title>
    <link>https://weareknytt.com/blog/UX-design-in-board-games</link>
    <description>The term UX design is most commonly used in the context of web and app design, and thus, may not be what comes to mind in relation to the very analog concept of board games. However, I believe that, in many regards, the exact same principles apply to both fields.</description>
  </item>
</channel>

</rss>
